







Current Location: Pune

Total Experience: 7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Pref. Location: Ahmedabad.Mumbai.Pune

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science and

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Engineering]

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Full Stack Developer, Tech Lead, Software Development, Application Programming, Application

Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Java, Maven, Spring

Boot, Hibernate, Jenkins, Junit, Cassandra, Oracle, MySQL, Rest API, Angularis, HTML, CSS

Verified : L. Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

# Summary

I have over 7+ years of experience in IT as a Front-End Engineer Role. Clients where I have developed the product from scratch to live which is used by the millions of customers was Brenntag, ING Bank, ABN AWRO, Bank of Ireland, Allstate Insurance, Deutsche Telekom. I started as a software engineer and has developed into a full stack developer more on the front end in a short time with his quick grasping and learning ability, not only in new technologies programming languages. I work as a front-end developer to help the other developer and has mostly focused on developing, building, automation testing, CICD phases, coaching team members for the shipment of the product successfully to the production environment and taking care after the production. Working in a challenging environment and has build, deployed and maintain infra of custom UI frameworks, Custom Web Components similar to AngularJS which have been utilized by the module team.

# Work Experience

Brenntag Group as Full Stack Developer Mar 2019 to Apr 2020

### Environment

React, React Native, RN libraries, Typescript, Redux, Saga, html5, css3, web components, jest, SASS, LESS, Nodejs, IX environment, Mongo dB, Rest API, Git, Java 8, Spring, Maven, Jenkin, Piccard, Cassandra, SEO, SEM, CRO, Optimizing Content, Corda, DLT, PostgreSQL, Ansible, Sonar, Fortify, power shell, Agile, Scrum, Jira, Confluence

### Activities

Working as front-end developer Lead role and dev-ops engineer, Architecture Designing, Architecture Presentation with POCs, Architecture Strategy, Tech-stacks selection, development CICD pipeline, the product from scratch to production within one year at E-commerce scaleup company for the project Brenntag connect E-commerce and Brenntag Source App, from this product customers can place orders of various chemicals products online with payments and download their orders, edit it and make the change with Brenntag Source. From the E-commerce App, customers can place online orders for chemicals in blockchain using Corda. Worked with the international's colleagues in Scrum model with agile way of working, daily stand-up, sprint planning, retro.

Capgemini as Software Developer Oct 2016 to Mar 2019

### Environment

React, Polymerjs, Typescript, LIT HTML, Lit element, OO JS, Web Components, redux, saga, state management, CSS3, SASS, LESS, jest, Gitlab with Kubernetes, Gitlab with docker, Cl/CD third party, bash script, Cassandra, Node JS, Java 8, Spring MMC, REST API, GIT, SVN, Jenkin, Piccard, Ansible, Sonar, Fortify, power shell, bash scripting,

# Activities

Working for Assisted channels for the LISA, RINGO and Kijklas project. Developing, building and deploying frontend application using polymerjs, lit html using various web components from the ING marketplace and pushing our own custom reusable web components for the internal employer of ING to serve the ING customers better. Project is basically migrating from Angular to Polymer. Also played a role of guiding front end developers to make them use of polymer after Angular and lit html so that backend developer also put hands on frontend side.

# 1

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. October 2017 - October 2018 (Netherlands) Client ABN AMRO Bank via Capgemini Role Front End Engineer Environment React, OO JS, functional, React Native, typescript, Web Components, BackBase, HTML5, CSS3, redux, saga, SASS, LESS, JASMNE, AWS, Node js, Java 8, Spring MVC, REST API, Jenkins, AWS, S3 Bucket, EC2, Graphql query, REST API, CI/CD, Redux, saga, Selenium Activities I was working for Tikkie app development as Front-end developer using technologies React framework, React Native for mobile development, Java, Spring MVC, Hibernate, AWS, CI/CD, Webpack, babel, typescript, javascript, html5, css3. I am responsible for developing Dashboard of Tikkie app, module and designing the webpages & custom web. The project was migrating from Angular to react framework, in the sprint I worked almost both the framework. React Native was the dominant development side.

October 2016 - October 2017 (India) Client Bank of Ireland via Capgemini Role Full stack developer Environment React, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, typescript, Polyfills, Web Components, OCJS, git, Java 8, Oracle server 2008, REST API, MVM, entity framework, jasmine unit test, Junit, SOA based architecture, Temenos Edgeconnect, T24 Web services, Jenkins, Ansible, WebDriverlO, Fortify, Microsoft Azure, Building cloud environment on Azure using Terraform, Packer, Puppet, Setup automated monitoring environment, YAML config, Cassandra, NoSQL, CI/CD Activities Requirement gathering and solution framing, estimations. Designing and developing particular web page reference to wireframe. Developing Custom components and putting it in BOI marketplace and making it available for other developers for reusability. Fast moving Agile development of Responsive web development for all breakpoints. Implement best programming practices in software engineering. Integration with web services and micro services. Consuming Rest API after testing with mock-data for API. Unit testing of Angular Development.

#### Deutsche Telekom Healthcare Solutions as Software Developer Mar 2016 to Oct 2016

Environment Angular2+, NgRx, RxJs, AB testing, HTML5, CSS3, Typescript, Javascript Activities To meet the product development deadline in every sprint. Test driven development including REST API as well as UI. To give demo of my assigned stories after sprint. To coordinate and help new developer. The application is used by 2000 hospitals of Germany from patient level to administration level of hospitals. Migrating windows applications into the web application after developing Custom Angular Framework. This application is developed to managed documents, patient, patients' cases, printing x-rays report, generating report at different editor level on the go.

^ Back to Top

# **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Punjab Technical University (PTU) in 2013

^ Back to Top

# IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last	Used	Experience
Angularjs, Angular 2+,			
JavaScript, TypeScript			
RxJs, NgRx, Jasmine			
HTML/CSS, Nodejs			
Jest, Junit			
Confluence, IntelliJ,			
WebDriverIO, Edipse			
Java 8, Maven			
Spring Boot, Hibernate			
Jenkins, Junit, Sonar			
TFS, Cassandra, Oracle			
MySQL, Rest API			
Oracle, Postgres, NoSQL			
McroServices			
Gitlab, docker, Kubernetes			
Ansible, puppet, GIT version			
Cucumber, Fortify			

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Dutch				

^ Back to Top

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

# ^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.